We've been married for 3 years, together
for 12, and today we're going to talk
about our Korean-style wedding.
Actually, we didn't really want to have
a wedding ceremony because we were
already legally married.
>> And I thought it's just a little bit of
waste of time and it costs usually like
crazy amount of money. We would like to
use that money towards something like a
experience or travel or something like
that.
>> Yeah, I wanted that money to go towards
our honeymoon.
>> But then my mom like keep pushing. They
really want me to like have a ceremony
in Changwon with the family members and
their like friends and colleagues and
stuff. So, we decided why not?
>> Yeah.
>> You know, it could be a good experience
for her too.
>> And it was. Actually, that was probably
one of the first culture shocks with the
wedding. To me, it seems like in Korea,
it's not just for the bride and the
groom. It's for the whole family. Cuz I
think in the US, maybe we're a little
bit more selfish when it comes to that.
It's like whatever the bride wants. And
here it seems like the whole family is
kind of involved.
>> Think about my parents. Over 30 years,
they went to all the friends' sons' or
daughters' weddings and then they paid
lots of money. They want to like try and
get some money for us too. And also,
it's kind of like, "Oh, my eldest son
[music] is getting married." and they
want to show their friends and maybe a
little show off too, you know.
>> Actually, I didn't know some of the
people at our wedding.
>> Me, neither.
>> I had attended weddings before in Korea,
so I knew that you don't really give
gifts, you give money. In the US,
there's a gift table, so it's not just
like everyone is expected to pay cash.
Usually, we have a gift registry, so we
know what the bride and groom want for
their house and then people buy off that
list. But,
yeah, I was really surprised. I don't
know if this is normal, but you kept an
Excel spreadsheet
>> [laughter]
>> with like who attended the wedding and
how much money they gave.
>> Yes, cuz I don't want to be like a
person who forgot to give them money,
you know? I don't want to be mean
person, you know?
>> Cheapskate?
>> Yeah, like I usually try to send more
money than what I received.
>> It's a little tricky. I think it's hard
to navigate the money part.
>> really care about the money we getting,
but I was very careful about the money
we're spending on the wedding. I just
like rent whatever random tux the hotel
gave me for free.
>> Oh, that's good.
>> Thank you. We really trying to budget
the ceremony.
>> For me, our Korean wedding was very
extravagant still, and I think my family
who was there would agree. So, I think
we got good bang for our buck. In the
US, we have an engagement photo shoot,
but not in a wedding dress. But yeah, I
wore three dresses, lots of outfit
changes. I had my own personal hair
stylist, my own makeup artist. Your
friend took our photos. I was really
kind of nervous. I know it might sound
weird cuz I'm always filming for
YouTube, but I'm kind of camera shy. And
he made the shoot so fun, and even
though it was such a long day, I had a
blast. I would get married again just
for the photo shoot.
>> I liked it because we changed spot a lot
cuz we were filming at the pojang and
then we were crossing the street.
>> That was fun. I actually legit drank
soju during our photo [laughter] shoot.
And I was kind of worried not just about
like the photo shoot itself, but
afterwards because Korean Photoshop, it
looks good, but I just wanted to still
look like myself. I didn't want too much
>> Photoshop?
>> Yeah, I mean they definitely touched
things up, but we still look like
ourselves. So, I was happy with that.
>> They made me little taller. I was happy
with that.
>> [laughter]
>> It was kind of funny because when we got
those back, of course, I was so excited.
So, I posted them on my social media and
all of my friends commented on it and
they were like, "Oh my gosh,
congratulations. Wait, you got married?"
Cuz at that point, I hadn't invited
anyone to what the wedding. Everyone was
like, "Oh my gosh, what? When did this
happen?" It's because I'm in a wedding
dress. That's not typical in the US.
It's more like showing off the ring. We
do a lot of like these poses.
>> Cuz in in Korea, you usually take a
photo shoot. You got to make the
invitation and then the photo frame to
decorate the venue. Like some guy didn't
even propose even at that point, too.
>> Wow. Yeah, the timelines are so
different in the US versus Korea. How
was it seeing me in a wedding dress for
the first time?
>> She was amazing.
>> Mhm. Fun fact, during that photo shoot,
one of those dresses that I wore, that
was my favorite wedding dress. Even more
so than the one I wore during the
ceremony.
>> That's because it's n times more
expensive than the one you're wearing.
>> Okay, okay.
>> [laughter]
>> I think one cultural difference is also
in Korea, to invite people, we call it
like a wedding invitation gathering. I
just think it's a little bit of a waste
of time and money. If people caring, you
will come to the wedding. If not, you
will send a message like congrats. So,
if those gathering decide your
relationship, I don't think it's a
healthy relationship. So, I did only two
cuz uh those people are coming from
Seoul to Changwon. So, I was like, I
appreciate you coming all the way to
Changwon.
>> I guess in the US, the closest thing to
that would be Well, there's nothing
really close to it. It's Korean culture
for sure.
>> What was the wedding like for you?
>> I was very skeptical at first because
I've attended a lot of Korean weddings
and they just seem very fast, very
inefficient. There's no party
afterwards. To be completely honest, I
thought maybe they weren't super
intimate, but at the end of the day, I
had a really great experience. I liked
that everything was very easy. So,
usually when I think of American
weddings, it's very stressful, but in
Korea, I actually didn't have to worry
about anything at all that day. I know
your mother and you both put in work
before
>> Mhm.
>> to make it run so smoothly. The other
thing that I liked is just seeing kind
of the merging of our cultures and our
families. My mom, my sister, my
brother-in-law, my grandma, they all
came from the US. My mom and my grandma
wore hanboks. My sister gave a speech.
My friend Daho was the announcer, and
she spoke in Korean and in English. So,
she had a really hard job. Yeah.
>> I think a lot of the participants, like
especially the older people there, maybe
were shocked actually, cuz we did it
like untraditionally some of the parts.
I mean, usually the moms walk down the
aisle and like light up, but then your
grandma did it with my mom. That was
kind of cute.
>> And my mom walked me down the aisle. I
mean, that's different in the US as
well, but my dad wasn't able to make it
just because it's obviously so far away.
I was getting my hair and makeup done,
and I talked to my dad on the phone. He
started tearing up. I could hear him
getting choked up when he was talking.
And then I just started crying, and the
makeup ladies were like, "No, no, don't
cry." I was like, "I got to go, Dad.
Bye."
>> Mhm.
>> Of course, like I I missed my dad there
a lot, and he probably would have walked
me down the aisle if he had been there.
But it was cool having my mom walk me
down the aisle, as well.
>> So, the wedding day.
>> In the morning, I, of course, got my
hair and makeup done. Really happy with
how they did it. I went and sat in the
bridal room. And one thing that really
surprised me about Korean weddings is
that you see the bride before she walks
down the aisle. That's like a big no in
the US. I think in the US that is the
part of the wedding that everybody is
most excited for though is the moment
when the groom sees his bride for the
first time. It's usually a very
emotional part of weddings in the US.
The grooms will cry. In the beginning I
tried to have it like that. But then it
was just like we got to take a photo. I
said okay, I'll compromise.
>> They're going to kick us out after 30
minutes, you know? So we got to take
photo beforehand.
>> So yeah, you saw me before and and then
it was just you're on, no practice. But
I was so nervous and I could hear your
entrance.
>> That was weird. I was in the very dark
room.
And then the lights are going crazy and
then they opened up the automatic door
and then I'm like walk down the aisle.
>> And then I entered. That was it. So then
the ceremony was starting. We did not
say vows. We had actually said our vows
in private before. Because I felt like I
could be a little bit more vulnerable
and sincere in private.
>> Usually in the Korean wedding somebody
else is singing for us. Since my dad is
playing saxophone, I was like you
playing saxophone and then I will sing.
>> Contello. Follow him on YouTube. His dad
is a really good saxophone player. So
yeah, we'll link his YouTube.
>> You didn't know I was going to sing?
>> I didn't. We were in Changwon for
something, trying on the dresses,
something like that. And you suddenly
ditched us. You were like oh no, I'm not
going to go.
>> For 1 month my dad and I practiced
separately. We got to at least do one
rehearsal, so that's why we came.
>> It definitely was everybody's favorite
part of the wedding. Actually, one
detail we didn't talk about is we were
live streaming the whole ceremony
because a lot of my friends and family
from back home couldn't attend. My
grandpa stayed up until like midnight to
watch the wedding [snorts] on live
stream. My mom and grandma, they've
never been bowed to. So, they both had
the waterworks coming when you bowed to
them.
>> Mhm.
>> That was the end of the ceremony,
but then we put on the very traditional
hanboks.
>> Hanbok.
>> And then the family threw chestnuts and
we had to catch it with the train of our
dress. And we caught three chestnuts, so
we're going to have three daughters.
>> [cheering]
>> At least we'll have daughters, not sons.
I have a younger brother, so knowing my
mom, like raising two sons,
>> I don't know.
And then it was buffet time. We just
went around and said hello to everybody.
It rained that day. In the US, it's good
luck if it rains on your wedding day,
and it poured.
>> I think it's in Korea too, like that.
>> Is it?
>> Yeah.
>> One similarity.
>> I was really touched because we had
friends coming from Seoul, from Vietnam,
from Hong Kong.
>> I love you guys.
>> Yes, we love you. So, we thought we
weren't going to have any weddings. And
actually, this wedding we're talking
about was just our first wedding.
>> We ended up did two weddings.
>> Should we have a third?
Actually, I think the second wedding was
really fun and interesting, but it was a
lot more work.
>> More work for who?
>> We will talk about that in the next
episode, though.
>> So, we did a American-style wedding in
Seoul.
>> So, stay tuned for the next one, and we
will see you then. Thank you for
watching.
>> Bye.